（リー）サクラさん。
（サクラ）何？
Sakura…
What is it?
本当のこと　ナルト君に言ったほうが
よかったんじゃないでしょうか。
Perhaps it would have been
better to tell Naruto the truth.
そんなこと
言えるわけないじゃない。
There's no way
I could have told him.
絶対にダメよ。
Absolutely no way.
（キバ）サクラ
オメエは　ナルトをなめすぎだ。
Sakura…
You're underestimating Naruto.
サスケを見つけたぜ。
I found Sasuke.
隣には　あのトビってのもいる。
That Tobi guy is next to him.
みんな　一度止まって。
Stop, everyone!
どうした？　なんで止まる。
What's wrong? Why did you stop?
フォーメーションは確認済みだろ。
We already went over our formation.
Kiba… What is Sasuke's precise location?
キバ　サスケ君のいる場所の
正確な位置は？
真北に向かって２時の方向。
Facing directly north,
he's at 2 o'clock.
１キロ先だ。
そう。
Up one kilometer.
Okay.
《みんな　ごめん》
Forgive me, everyone!
やっぱり　これで　みんなを
眠らせる気だったんですね。
I knew it.
You were going to use this
to make everyone fall asleep,
weren't you?
サイ。
（キバ）はぁ？
Sai!
Huh?!
（赤丸）ワンワン！
どういうことです？
What's going on?
サクラは１人で　サスケにケリをつけようと
考えていたようです。
Sakura was going to take care
of Sasuke herself.
なんで　１人でやろうとした？
Why would you go alone?
Yes, why?
We promised to do it together!
そうです　僕たちみんなでやるって
約束でしたよ。
No, you can't.
いや　ダメだよ。
ここから先は誰も行かせない。
I won't let anyone proceed.
どうして？
コイツ。
Why not?
You… I always thought
you were suspicious.
やっぱ
うさんくせぇヤツだと思ったぜ。
僕たちだけじゃ　サスケにも
そのトビってのにも勝てやしない。
The four of us alone are no match
against Sasuke or this Tobi.
カカシ先生に
行かせないと約束した。
I promised Kakashi Sensei that
I wouldn't let any of you go.
What?
なんですって？
そういうことかよ。
Is that the reason?
サイ　一度しか言わない。
Sai…
I'll say this only once.
そこをどいて。
Move aside.
急がないと
少々やばい状況です。
We must hurry.
It's becoming
a rather dire situation.
ダメだ　行かせない。
No.
I won't let you go.
忍法　超獣戯画！
Ninja Art: Super Beast Scroll!
ヘビで
しめあげようということですね。
You're going to bind us
with those snakes?
カカシ先生の言うことも　わかるが→
I understand where
Kakashi Sensei's coming from,
そう何度も
サスケを野放しにできるかよ。
but we just can't keep
letting Sasuke go.
俺がケリをつけてやる。
ク～ン。
I'll take care of him!
なんでだよ　赤丸
ビビってんじゃねえよ。
Why not, Akamaru?!
Don't be so scared!
犬のほうが賢いようだね。
The dog is smarter.
僕の言うことを
わかってくれたようだ。
It seems he understands
what I'm saying.
うっせえ！
いくよ　リーさん。
Shut up!
Let's go, Lee.
Sure thing! Yeah!
いくぞ　うおぉ～！
こんなもん通牙で。
（リー）いい陽動になりました　キバ君。
I'll take care of this
with Tunneling Fang!
Good diversion, Kiba!
ホイヤーさっと！
Here!
しまった！
Damn it!
うわっ！
ワンワン！
みんな　ごめんね。
I'm sorry…everyone.
《キバや　リーさんごと…》
Kiba and Lee too.
She got us. Please hurry!
やられました　急いでください。
（カカシ）やるね　サクラ。
I'm impressed, Sakura.
Sakura's Resolve
Sasuke…
《サスケ君　私は　サスケ君を
いつ好きになったんだろう。
When did I fall in love
with you?
あの頃の私は
クールなサスケ君に憧れ→
Back in those days,
I was just infatuated with
how cool you were.
かっこいいと思うだけだった》
((みんな　聞いて　聞いて！
Listen up, everyone!
私　好きな人ができたの！
誰だと思う？
I'm in love!
Who do you think it is?
手短に話せ。
サスケ君とか言わないでよ。
Keep it brief.
And don't say it's Sasuke.
えっ　何でわかったの？
How did you know?
（イルカ）じゃ　次７班
春野サクラ　うずまきナルト！
Next, Team 7.
Sakura Haruno,
Naruto Uzumaki.
（ナルト）やった～！
（イルカ）それと　うちはサスケ。
Yes!
And Sasuke Uchiha.
(しゃ～　んなろ！))
Cha!
Then…you became my teammate.
《サクラ：そして　私は
サスケ君と仲間になった》
((私は　春野サクラ。
I'm Sakura Haruno.
好きなものはっていうか
好きな人は　え～と→
What I like...
I mean, who I like is...
My future dream is...
将来の夢も言っちゃおうかな。
(キャーッ！))
《サクラ：第７班として》
On Team 7.
((ここに鈴が２つある。
Today's assignment is
これを俺から　昼までに
奪い取ることが課題だ。
to take these bells away
from me by noon.
もし　昼までに俺から鈴を
奪えなかったヤツは　昼飯抜き！
Those who can't do it
won't get lunch.
（サスケ）ほらよ。
Here.
H-Hey, Sasuke.
Sensei just said…
ちょっと　サスケ君　先生が…。
大丈夫だ。
今は　アイツの気配はない。
It's okay.
There's no sign of him now.
昼からは３人で鈴を取りにいく。
In the afternoon, the three of us
will go and get the bells.
足手まといになられちゃ
こっちが困るからな。
It'll be trouble for me
if he becomes a hindrance, so...
《サスケ君…》
Sasuke…
何だ！？
お前ら～！
What?!
You guys!
キャーッ！
合格。
You pass.
はっ？
We passed?! Why?!
合格？　なんで！？
忍は　裏の裏を読むべし。
A ninja must see through deception.
忍の世界で　ルールや掟を破るヤツは
クズ呼ばわりされる。
In the ninja world, those who break
the rules are scum.
(けどな　仲間を大切にしないヤツは
それ以上のクズだ))
But those who abandon
their friends are worse than scum.
《仲間になっても私は同じだった。
Being teammates didn't change me.
ただただ
かっこいいサスケ君が好きだった。
I was still hopelessly in love
with the cool Sasuke.
クールな　あの横顔を
見つめているだけでよかった。
Just gazing at his handsome profile
was enough for me.
陰りのある　その表情の裏に
何があったかなんて→
I never gave a thought
to who he really was behind
that pensive face.
まるで考えもせずに。　でも…》
But…
((大蛇丸：サスケ君は必ず私を求める。
力を求めてね。
Sasuke will definitely come
looking for me…
in search of power.
ぐわっ！
アンタ　サスケ君に何をしたのよ！？
You! What did you do to Sasuke?
別れのプレゼントをあげたのよ。
I gave him a parting gift.
うわ！
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
うわ～！
サスケ君！
S-Sasuke?!
しっかりして　サスケ君！
Hang on, Sasuke!
(ねえ！
ううっ！))
Please!
((俺は　ようやく理解した。
俺は復讐者。
At last I understand.
I'm an avenger.
たとえ
悪魔に身をゆだねようとも→
With the path I'm on,
I must acquire power at any price,
力を手に入れなきゃならない
道にいる。
even if it means being
consumed by evil.
残るは　お前だけだ。
You're the only one left.
お前は　もっと楽しませてくれよ。
Make it a little more fun for me.
やめて！
Stop!
Stop it, please!
お願い　やめて。
このアザのことは黙ってろ。
Don't say anything about
this bruise.
Why are you pretending
to be tough?
どうして　そう強がるのよ？
I don't want to watch you suffer
all the time anymore!
ずっと苦しんでるサスケ君なんて
もう見たくない。
私には　サスケ君が…。
お前には　関係ねえだろ。
To me, you are…
This has nothing to do with you!
(余計なお世話なんだよ！))
Mind your own business.
((サスケ君！))
Sasuke!
《サスケ君が抱えていた影。
The shadow that you carried…
それに　やっと気づいたときには
もう遅かった》
When I finally noticed,
it was too late.
((な　なんだよ？
W-What?!
俺と今から戦え。
Fight me… Right now!
ちょうどいいってばよ。
This is perfect, I was just thinking
that I wanted to fight you!
俺も　お前とやりたいと
思ってたとこだ！
クソが！
Damn it!
２人とも　やめて！
Stop it, both of you!
さっきの千鳥　同じ里の仲間に
向ける大きさじゃなかったが。
That Chidori you used earlier…
It was bigger than what
you'd normally direct
at a comrade from the same village.
(ナルトを殺す気だったのか？))
Were you thinking of killing Naruto?
Naruto knew…
He knew about your shadow.
《ナルトは　知っていた。
サスケ君の影に気づいていた》
((サクラちゃん
ジャマしないでくれってばよ))
Sakura…
Don't interfere.
Before I knew it,
《知らない間に
ナルトは成長して→
Naruto had matured and was
standing face-to-face with you.
サスケ君に正面から向き合っていた。
２人に置いてきぼりにされたまま
それでも私は変わらなかった》
I was the one left behind.
Yet I didn't change.
((俺は　お前たちとは違う。
I'm not the same as you.
お前たちとは
相容れない道にいる。
I'm traveling a path the rest
of you can't follow.
私は　サスケ君が好きで
好きでたまらない！
I love you so much, Sasuke!
サスケ君が　私と一緒にいてくれれば
絶対　後悔させない！
If you stay with me,
I won't let you regret it,
no matter what!
毎日　楽しくするし
絶対　幸せになるはずだから。
Everyday will be fun
and we'll be happy!
復讐だって手伝う！
I'll even help you get revenge!
I'll make it happen somehow,
I promise you!
絶対　私が
なんとかしてみせるから！
だから　ここに→
So please…
私と一緒に…。
Stay here with me.
And if you can't…
それが　ダメなら
私も一緒に連れてって。
take me with you.
やっぱり　お前　うざいよ。
You're still annoying.
サスケ君を→
Please…
サスケ君を連れ戻して。
Please bring Sasuke back.
サスケは　ぜってぇ
俺が連れて帰る！
I'll bring Sasuke back without fail!
(一生の約束だってばよ！))
I promise that on my life!
《何も考えず　ただナルトに
重荷を背負わせてしまった》
I didn't think about it and
I put the entire burden on Naruto.
《私は　泣きついただけ。
I went crying to you.
あなたに頼って
すがりついただけ》
I held onto you, expecting you
to make it all better.
《自分じゃ何も…。
While I did nothing.
だから　今度はって…》
That's why this time…
((ごめん　ナルト。
I'm sorry, Naruto.
少し待たせることに
なっちゃうけど→
You may have to wait for me
a little bit.
(今度は　私も一緒に))
Next time I'm coming with you.
《２人に追いつこうと
私なりに頑張った》
I tried to catch up to the two of you
in my own way.
《でも　サスケ君は→
But Sasuke…
私たちの思いを超えて→
is no longer
the person we think he is
もう届かない場所にいた》
and he's far beyond our reach.
((サクラちゃんとの約束が
なくなっても　関係ねえよ！
It doesn't matter,
even if there's no promise
between us anymore.
俺は　俺自身で
サスケを助けたいと思ってる。
I personally want to save Sasuke.
(もういい！　私は帰る！))
Forget it! I'm going back.
《ナルト…　ごめんね。
Naruto… I'm sorry!
そして　ありがとう。
But also…thank you.
でも　私は決めた！
But I've already decided.
I'll take care of Sasuke myself!
この手でサスケ君を…　私が！》
（マダラ）危なかったな。
That was a close call.
((ダンゾウ：忍の世のため
木ノ葉のため→
For the sake of the ninja world…
for sake of the Hidden Leaf…
お前らは決して
生かしてはおかぬ！
I will not let you both live!
《これは裏四象封印術！》
This is the Reverse Tetragram
Sealing Jutsu.
(サスケ　ダンゾウから離れろ！))
Sasuke! Get away from Danzo!
あれは自分の死体に
引きずり込んで封印する→
That was the Collateral Damage
Sealing Jutsu.
He would've dragged you into
his corpse and sealed you inside.
道連れ封印術。
己の死に際で発動するように
術式を組んでいたようだ。
He probably set it up to activate
at the moment of his death.
危なかったな。
That was close.
次だ　木ノ葉へ向かう。
We'll head for Hidden Leaf Village next.
木ノ葉ね。
The Hidden Leaf, huh?
俺は　コイツの眼を持っていく。
I'm taking his eye.
サスケ　お前も焦らず
アジトに帰って休め。
Sasuke, don't be hasty.
Go back to the hideout and rest.
瞳力の使いすぎだ。
You used up too much of
your visual prowess.
いずれ強がっては
いられなくなるぞ。
Eventually you won't be
able to keep it up.
光を失いかけている　その眼。
Your eye is losing its light.
１人で行って何ができる？
What can you do by yourself now?
目的を達成するには
我慢も必要だ。
Patience is necessary
to reach one's goal.
♪～
サスケ　ひとつ忠告しておく。
Sasuke…
I'm going to give you a bit of advice.
あの女。
That woman…
いらないなら　ちゃんと
とどめを刺しておけ。
If you don't need her,
make sure you finish her off.
我らのことを知りすぎている。
She knows too much about us.
我らだと？
俺がいつ　お前の仲間になった。
"Us"? When did I join you?
フッ　まぁいい。
Well, nevermind.
また会おう。
We'll meet again.
♪～
EARTH
((香燐：ねぇ　みんなどこ？
Hey! Where is everyone?!
獅子連弾！
Lion's Barrage!
俺たちと同じ地の書か。
An Earth Scroll, just like us, huh?
《メ　メガネ…》
M-My glasses!
じゃあな。
– Later.
《もう一度　あのときの顔が→
I wish I could've seen your face
from back then,
見たかったな》
just one more time.
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
サクラか。
It's you, Sakura.
《昔と　まるで感じが違う。
He feels totally different.
これがサスケ君？》
Is this really Sasuke?
何しに俺の前に来た？
What are you doing here?
《コイツは…》
Who is she?
サスケ君！
Sasuke!
私もサスケ君についていく。
I'm coming with you!
I'm deserting the Hidden
木ノ葉を抜ける。
チャンピオンが１ラウンドでノックアウト！？
ったく　情けないわね。
闘魂が足んないのよ　闘魂が！
（サイ）相手の耳もとで
そっとささやくか。
なるほど。
あのさ…。
パンチはこうやって　腰で打つ！
グホッ！
ああ！　ご　ごめんサイ。　大丈夫？
わざとじゃないのよ。
ちょっと　気をしっかり。
う～ん…　お宝写真　袋とじか。
すっげえ気になる！
くそっ　どうにか見えねえかな？
白眼！
って…　俺に使えるわけねえか。
しようがねえな。
ちょっと　サイったら起きてよ！
どれどれ…　気になる中身は？
どこがお宝だ　金返せ！
（くもじい）もしもし
そこのあなた。
たまには　空から
日本を眺めてみるというのは→
どうじゃろう？
人気観光スポットの裏側や→
ふだんは立入禁止の場所を
探検するぞ。
（くもみ）テレビ初！？　何これ！